so this is a lesson on improving cash
performance there are many methods for
improving cash performance but in
general they can be grouped in three
categories and these three categories
have to do with the average memory
access time or a mat which is equal to
hit time plus miss rate times miss
penalty of a cache so pretty much if we
always hit we get the hit time if we
miss we get the Miss penalty and how
often we miss is the Miss rate and the
average memory access time as seen by
the processor is equal to this so the
methods for improving cache performance
can be those that try to reduce the hit
time those that try to reduce the Miss
rate or trying to reduce the Miss
penalty all of these would reduce the
average memory access time which
improves the overall performance of the
processor when it needs to access the
cache